The path to becoming a pediatrician begins much as it does for any other medical specialty.
You start with a four year course of study at a college or university.
During your bachelor's or undergraduate course of study you'll really want to focus on keeping your GPA at 3.75 or above, as medical school is highly competitive.
As you, when you're in completion of your undergraduate experience you'll need to take what is called the Medical College Admissions Test.
This is a standardized test that all applicants to medical school must take.
It covers the physical sciences, biological sciences, verbal reasoning, and written communication.
If you did not major in a science discipline, then you'll need to make sure that you've completed all of the science prerequisites to prepare you for the MCAT.
Once you have taken the MCAT, you need to actually apply to medical school, and this; again, is a standard process.
Most of the medical schools in the United States par participate in what's called AMCAS, and you can apply to one or all of those schools through the application service.
Once you have applied to medical school and are accepted, you'll begin your formal medical training, which is an additional four year course of study beyond your undergraduate education.
The first two years of medical school focus primarily on didactic instruction in health sciences, and the second two years focus primarily on clinical knowledge and skills.
Along the way, you'll need to pass both parts of the United States Medical License Exam, Step 1, covering your basic knowledge of health sciences, and part 2, covering your basic knowledge of clinical skills.
Upon completion of medical school you will become an MD; however, you're not ready to practice yet as a pediatrician.
To practice as a pediatrician, you need to apply to a residency program in pediatrics.
This is a period of graduate medical education, during which you learn your specialty.
In pediatrics, it's a three year residency requirement, and some may, particularly if in interested in a sub-specialty in pediatrics or in an academic career may choose to complete a fellowship beyond that.
Once you've completed a residency, and or fellowship, your graduate medical education is complete, and you can take the state board exam in the state in which you want to practice, and you will be able to to practice independently as a pediatrician.